Hao Wu

School of Computer Science and Engineering University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC) Chengdu, China Tel & WeChat: (+86) 178-6680-6572 wh.pyjnqd@gmail.com

Bio. I am currently a third-year graduate student under the supervision of **Lianli Gao** at the Department of Department of Computer Science, UESTC. My research interests lie in the field of computer vision, especially in **medical image analysis** and **few-shot learning**. My personal website is here.

Education

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC)

M.Phil Computer Science and Technology GPA: 3.76/4.0

Shandong University (SDU) 2017—2021

B.Eng. Computer Science and Technology (Elite Program) GPA: 89.12/100

Experience

Center for Future Media, UESTC 2021.09—Present

Advisor: Lianli Gao

Focus: Few-shot learning, representation learning, in-context learning

Institute of Intelligent Computing, SDU 2019.09—2021.06

Advisor: Yanwei Zheng

Focus: Person ReID, AI applications on Power System

Intelligent Media Research Center, SDU 2018.10—2019.05

Advisor: Xuemeng Song

Focus: Competition(network compression)

Publication

- 1. Xu Luo*, **Hao Wu***, Ji Zhang, Lianli Gao, Jing Xu, Jingkuan Song. A Closer Look at Few-shot Classification Again. Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML2023)
- 2. **Hao Wu**, Danyang Feng and Huihui Fang. Glaucoma Detection on 3D-OCT with View Transform. The 10th Ophthalmic Medical Image Analysis Workshop, MICCAI 2023.

Projects

1. Early Glaucoma Detection with Fundus and 3D-OCT Images, Chengdu, China 2022.12

Researcher. We are committed to detecting glaucoma through the use of multimodal medical data, including Optical Coherence Tomography(OCT) and Fundus.

2. Multi-view based Coal Measurement System, Shandong, China

2020.12

R&D Engineer. Coal Measurement offers a reliable coal volume estimation, enabling effective scheduling of power plant operations. We has successfully developed a multi-view based measurement system, incorporating over 100 cameras to achieve cost-effective 3D modeling. Through the implementation of advanced algorithms in camera calibration, feature mining and matching, and dense reconstruction, we have achieved less than 10% error with 10% budget.

3. System of Active Hazard Detection in Nanding Thermal Power Plant, Shandong, China

2020.10

R&D Engineer. The active hazard detection system in power plant seamlessly integrates visual signals from CCTV monitors with advanced visual intelligent methods, enabling a highly effective sub-second response. This system has been successfully operational for 2 years.

4. An Amazing Auto-Typesetting System[Project Page]

2019.05

R&D Engineer. DLArtist is an innovative auto-typesetting system that liberates specialists from the burdensome task of manual typesetting. With DLArtist, all you need to do is gather the necessary text and image materials, import them into the system, and then sit back and wait. In just a matter of seconds, you will be amazed to witness the transformation of your content into a beautifully designed magazine article. This project ranked 9th in the 12th National Collegiate Software Innovation Contest and got investment intention.

Scholarships & Honors

- 2023 & 2021 First Class Scholarship of UESTC (2 times)
- 2021 College Graduate Excellence Award of Shandong University (only 1 in each class)
- 2020 Rank 1st, The 3rd Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition of SDU (Investment Intention Got)
- 2019 National Second Prize (9/199), The 12th National Collegiate Software Innovation Contest
- 2019 Second Class Scholarship of SDU (2 times)
- 2019 Zhiyang Scholarship (only 3 at each grade)
- 2018 China National Encouragement Scholarship
- 2018 First Class Scholarship of SDU

Misc

- 2019 First Aider of China Red Cross
- 2020 Teaching assistant of Linear Algebra
- 2021 Teaching assistant of Discrete Mathematics
- 2020-2023 Lab Server Administrator

2020 I was the co-leader of OpenLab, our undergraduate lab. During COVID-19 pandemic, I have invited a dozen speakers from China and America, and held 8 webinars online for our lab.

2020-2021 I established the first **Stray Cat Rescue Team** in Shandong University and it has rescued dozens of stray cats in our campus.

Language: CET-4 (Pass), CET-6 (Pass, 485), IELTS (I'm working on it)

Programming: Python, Java, SQL, Shell, LATEX

Hobbies: Riding (I rode around my city for 106 kilometers); Climbing (I have reached a 4100-meters' mountain, and plan to climb a 5276-meters' mountain in one year); Reading; Walking